- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crash,
birds cooing]
[海浪拍打，
鸟儿咕咕叫]
[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
[clams cooing]
[蛤蜊咕咕叫]
- [rhythmic yelling]
- [有节奏的喊叫]
Hey, Timmy.
嘿，蒂米。
I found your ball
and your sister.
我找到了你的球
还有你的妹妹。
- Hi!
- 你好！
- Yep.
- 是的。
[rhythmic yell]
- Whee!
[有节奏的喊叫]
- 呼！
both: [giggle]
Yeah!
两人：[咯咯笑]
是啊！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- A thousand pardons,
sir Sea Tiger.
- 一千次赦免，
海虎先生。
[squeals]
Oh.
[尖叫声]
哦。
[laughs]
[笑]
Yep.
[rhythmic yell]
是的。
[有节奏的喊叫]
[grunts]
And the elephant says...
[咕哝]
大象说……
- [moos]
- [laughs]
- [哞哞]
- [笑]
Whee!
哎哟！
The giraffe goes...
长颈鹿走了...
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
And the baboon says...
狒狒说……
- [quacks]
- [庸医]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Ha-ha!
哈哈！
And the zookeeper goes...
然后动物园管理员就走了……
- [growls]
Again with this kid!
- [咆哮]
又和这孩子在一起了！
How many times
do I have to tell you
多少次
我必须告诉你吗
to stay out
of the animal enclosures?
留在外面
动物围栏？
These are not pets!
这些不是宠物！
These are wild animals,
这些都是野生动物，
and you can get
seriously injured.
你可以得到
重伤。
- These little cuties are
dangerous?
- 这些小可爱们是
危险吗？
[laughs]
- [growls]
[笑]
- [咆哮]
- Don't be silly.
- 别傻了。
- Oh, that's it!
- 哦，就是这样！
[grunts]
[device beeps]
[咕哝]
[设备蜂鸣声]
- For me?
Thanks.
- 为我？
谢谢。
- No, it's not a gift.
It's an ankle alarm.
- 不，这不是礼物。
这是脚踝警报器。
And the next time
you try to sneak
而下一次
你试图偷偷摸摸
into the animal enclosures,
it's gonna do this...
进入动物围栏，
它会做这个...
[alarm blares]
- SpongeBob Alert.
[警报声]
- 海绵宝宝警报。
SpongeBob Alert.
海绵宝宝警报。
- Get it?
- Got it.
- 得到它？
- 知道了。
- Good.
- [yells]
- 好的。
- [大喊]
Whoa!
[grunts]
哇！
[咕哝]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[laughs]
[笑]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[hums]
[哼哼]
- [grunts]
- [squeaks]
- [咕哝]
- [吱吱声]
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
- [hums]
Huh?
- [哼哼]
啊？
Oh, no you don't!
哦，不，你不！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- [groans]
[all exclaiming]
- [呻吟]
[所有人惊呼]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[all shout]
[大家喊]
- [quacks]
- [庸医]
- That's it!
- [whimpering]
- 就是这样！
- [呜咽]
- You are banned from the zoo!
- 你被禁止进入动物园！
Get out!
出去！
Out, I say!
[wheezes]
出去，我说！
[喘息声]
- Yes, sir.
I'll go.
- 是的，先生。
我去吧。
[squeaks, whimpers]
[吱吱声，呜咽声]
- Hold it!
- 坚持住！
If he goes, I go.
如果他走，我就走。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
And you can keep
your dumb old peanuts.
并且你可以保留
你这些愚蠢的老花生。
[huffs]
Come on, SpongeBob.
[怒气]
来吧，海绵宝宝。
- And stay out!
- 留在外面！
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- Oh, that's it now.
Let it out.
- 哦，现在就是这样了。
把它放出来。
- I--I just wanna
pet the critters.
- 我--我只是想要
抚摸小动物。
Does that make me an animal?
[sobs]
这会让我成为动物吗？
[抽泣]
- That mean ol' zookeeper.
- 那是指老动物园管理员。
He looks like a monkey
and he smells like one too.
他看起来像一只猴子
他闻起来也像一个。
Ha, you should just make
your own zoo.
哈，你应该做
你自己的动物园。
- [sniffles]
My own zoo.
- [抽鼻子]
我自己的动物园。
That's a laugh.
[sniffles]
那是笑声。
[抽鼻子]
Ooh.
哦。
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
你在想吗
我在想什么？
- Ooh!
- [yelps]
- 哦！
- [尖叫声]
both: Bubble zoo!
两者：泡泡动物园！
- [inhales deeply, exhales]
- [深吸气，呼气]
- Ooh!
- Voilà!
- 哦！
- 瞧！
Our first zoo animals.
我们的第一个动物园动物。
- [laughs]
Ooh, ooh!
- [笑]
哦哦哦！
I get to name 'em!
我要给他们起名字！
Um, your name is Saucepan.
- Ooh.
嗯，你的名字是锅。
- 哦。
- Your name is Concrete,
and you're Debbie.
- 你的名字是混凝土，
你是黛比。
- [groans]
- Oh, I forgot they're bubbles!
- [呻吟]
- 哦，我忘了它们是泡泡！
[sobs]
[抽泣]
[mischievous music]
[恶作剧的音乐]
- Don't be a dope,
try extra strength soap.
- 别做个傻瓜
尝试使用强力肥皂。
[inhaling deeply]
[深吸一口气]
[exhaling]
[呼气]
[bubble penguin quacks]
- Oh.
[泡泡企鹅嘎嘎叫]
- 哦。
[grunting]
[bubble penguin squeaking]
[咕噜声]
[泡泡企鹅的吱吱声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
It worked!
It works!
成功了！
有用！
- It works!
It works!
- 有用！
有用！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[inhaling deeply]
[深吸一口气]
[exhaling]
[呼气]
Oh, look at 'em, Patrick,
so happy and healthy.
哦，看看他们，帕特里克，
如此快乐和健康。
Oh, and look, Patrick,
bubble droppings.
哦，看，帕特里克，
泡沫粪便。
- Oh.
Bubble droppings?
- 哦。
泡沫粪便？
[laughs]
[笑]
Ooh!
I'm popping poops!
哦！
我拉屎了！
[laughs]
Huh?
[笑]
啊？
Hey!
[bubble goat burps, bleats]
嘿！
[泡泡山羊打嗝、咩咩叫]
But I was gonna eat those.
但我本来想吃那些。
- No more "buts."
- 不再有“但是”。
We need more animals!
我们需要更多的动物！
[inhales sharply, exhales]
[猛吸气，呼气]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
Welcome to the Bubble Zoo,
欢迎来到泡泡动物园，
where the price of admission
is a smile.
入场费在哪里
是一个微笑。
- [squeaks]
- [吱吱声]
- Just a second, you.
- 等一下，你。
Ymm.
That's better.
嗯。
这样更好。
- Hello, folks.
- 大家好。
Please leave all
your sharp objects at the gate.
请全部留下
门口的尖锐物品。
Okay, Grandpa, spread 'em.
好吧，爷爷，传播它们。
[glove snaps]
- [gulps]
[手套按扣]
- [吞咽]
[old man grunting]
[老人咕哝]
[gasps]
Rascal.
[喘气]
无赖。
- Gather 'round, folks,
and meet the animals.
- 聚集在一起，伙计们，
并认识动物。
These wild bubble-phants
"never forget" to have fun.
这些野生的泡泡幻影
“永远不要忘记”玩得开心。
[laughs]
[bubble-phant trumpeting]
[笑]
[泡泡幻影的喇叭声]
Ah!
啊!
These bubble-raffes are
necking,
这些气泡拉夫是
颈缩，
and they have the necks for it.
他们有这个能力。
[laughs]
[笑]
[stopwatch beeping]
Ooh!
[秒表鸣响]
哦！
Time to feed the sea monsters.
是时候喂海怪了。
Oh, ally-zoop.[laughs]
哦，盟友动物园。[笑]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[inhales sharply, exhales]
[bubble chirping]
[猛吸气，呼气]
[泡泡叽叽喳喳]
Come and get it!
[bubble fish chomps]
快过来取！
【泡泡鱼咬碎】
- [chomps]
- [moans]
- [咀嚼]
- [呻吟]
[bubble monster chomps]
[泡泡怪物咀嚼]
[water splashes]
[水花四溅]
[bubble monster chuckles]
[泡泡怪物咯咯笑]
- Hi.
- 你好。
♪ ♪
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
- [yawning]
[bones cracking]
- [打哈欠]
[骨头碎裂]
Ooh.
♪ Up from my nap ♪
哦。
♪ 从午睡中醒来 ♪
♪ Ya-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 呀呀呀呀 ♪
♪ Getting my garden pants ♪
♪ 穿上我的花园裤 ♪
♪ Ya-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 呀呀呀呀 ♪
♪ Going out the door,
ya-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 走出家门，
呀呀呀呀♪
♪ Walking on the tongue ♪
♪ 用舌头行走 ♪
♪ Ya-ta-ta-ta ♪
♪ 呀呀呀呀 ♪
♪ That's a lot of teeth ♪
♪ 牙齿很多 ♪
Ya-ta-ta--ah!
呀呀呀呀啊！
What's happening?
发生什么事了？
[grunts]
- Hey, Squidward.
[咕哝]
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
I see you're playing
with the sea monsters.
我看你在玩
与海怪。
Isn't my bubble zoo fun?
我的泡泡动物园好玩吗？
- Get me out of here,
you moron!
- 带我离开这里
你这个白痴！
- Okay.
- 好的。
Oh, Maggie.
哦，玛吉。
Tickle, tickle,
let's put Squidward down.
痒痒，痒痒，
让我们把章鱼哥放下吧。
[bubble monster grunting]
[泡泡怪物的咕噜声]
Wow!
Aww.
哇！
哇。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[yelps]
Blech.
[尖叫声]
布莱赫。
- And Squidward is reborn.
- 章鱼哥重生了。
[all cheer]
- [groans]
[大家欢呼]
- [呻吟]
Now wait just a darn second.
Uh--
现在等一下。
呃——
[gasps]
[喘气]
[yelling]
[大喊]
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
[bubble rhino huffs]
[Squidward squeals]
[泡泡犀牛怒气冲冲]
[章鱼哥尖叫]
both: Look out, Squidward!
两人：小心，章鱼哥！
[bubble rhino growls]
[泡泡犀牛咆哮]
[Squidward whimpering]
[章鱼哥的呜咽声]
- Run for your lives!
[all clamoring]
- 为你的生命而奔跑！
[全都吵闹]
- Squidward,
don't forget to bring him back!
- 章鱼哥，
别忘了把他带回来！
[bubble animals roar]
[泡泡动物咆哮]
Nice, bubble beasts.
不错，泡泡兽。
Uh, let's make you
some more enclosures, huh?
呃，让我们让你
还有一些外壳，是吗？
[bubble animals roaring]
[泡泡动物咆哮]
- Would now be a good time
to talk about my hours?
- 现在是个好时机
谈谈我的工作时间？
- Stop those animals, Patrick.
- 阻止那些动物，帕特里克。
Go!
去！
- Huh?
Oh!
- 啊？
哦！
[bubble animals roaring]
[泡泡动物咆哮]
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
♪ ♪
[grunts softly]
Stop ani-mules!
[轻声咕哝]
别再用骡子了！
Stop!
停止！
Huh?
啊？
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[yelling]
[大喊]
But seriously, SpongeBob,
Thursdays are out.
但说真的，海绵宝宝，
周四已经出去了。
[bubble animals roaring]
[泡泡动物咆哮]
[perilous music]
[危险的音乐]
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
[bubble animals clamoring]
[泡泡动物叫嚣]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Take me customers,
but don't hurt me money!
带我去顾客，
但不要伤害我的钱！
[till beeping]
[直到发出嘟嘟声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Ahh!
啊！
♪ ♪
[bubble penguins buzzing]
[泡泡企鹅嗡嗡声]
- For hate's sake!
I spit my last breath at thee!
- 为了仇恨！
我向你吐出最后一口气！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
Ahh!
啊！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- Don't be so dramatic.
They're cute.
- 别这么戏剧化。
他们很可爱。
Wait!
等待！
[both yelling]
[两人大喊]
[bubble penguins buzzing]
[泡泡企鹅嗡嗡声]
[bubble animals roaring]
[泡泡动物咆哮]
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- SpongeBob, why are
the animals making scary faces?
- 海绵宝宝，为什么
动物们做着可怕的鬼脸？
- They've gone wild, Patrick!
- 他们太疯狂了，帕特里克！
Wild!
荒野！
- [yelling]
- [大喊]
- [rhythmic yelling]
- [有节奏的喊叫]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Hey!
This ain't no furlough.
嘿！
这不是休假。
Get back in your enclosures
right now!
回到你的围栏里
现在！
[animals roar]
[SpongeBob yells rhythmically]
[动物咆哮]
[海绵宝宝有节奏地喊叫]
Or whenever, you know.
I'm flexible.
或者无论什么时候，你知道。
我很灵活。
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [rhythmic yelling]
- [有节奏的喊叫]
- Look, SpongeBob,
it's the zoo animals!
- 看，海绵宝宝，
这是动物园里的动物！
- They must have heard
my uvula.
-他们一定听说过
我的小舌。
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
♪ ♪
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
[bubble animals whimpering]
[泡泡动物呜咽]
- You guys saved our lives!
- 你们救了我们的命！
- Thank you, ani-mules!
- 谢谢你，阿尼骡子！
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
- And thank you, SpongeBob,
- 谢谢你，海绵宝宝，
for bringing all my animalsback.
把我所有的动物带回来。
And I just love
the new animals too.
我就是喜欢
还有新动物。
You are welcome
at the zoo any time.
不客气
任何时间都可以去动物园。
I officially remove the ban.
我正式解除禁令。
[chuckles]
There you go.
[笑声]
就这样吧。
- I promise
you won't regret it,
- 我保证
你不会后悔的
Mr. Zookeeper, sir.
动物园管理员先生，先生。
[rhythmic yell]
[有节奏的喊叫]
I'm free again!
Free!
我又自由了！
自由的！
Good morning, Squidward.
- Good morning.
早上好，章鱼哥。
- 早上好。
[sighs]
It's a living.
[叹气]
这是一种生活。